Ester Beltrami

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

beltrami.ester@gmail.com ■

linkedin.com/in/beltramiester in

github.com/estyxx 🗘

@esterbeltrami 💆

I am a passionate full-stack developer with a degree in Computer Science and over 6+ years of experience building websites and products using **Python**, **GraphQL**, **React**, **Next.js** and **Typescript** as my favorite tech stack. In my free time, I also love to attend and help organize Python conferences such as PyCon Italia and contribute to open-source projects such as **strawberry-graphql** and **Poetry Package Manager**.

EXPERIENCE

MADE.COM - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

- Software development and design of the micro-services sitting behind the scenes of MADE.COM responsible for managing warehouses, carriers and shipping to the end customer.
- Working with different python frameworks like Starlette, Flask, Aiohttp, FastAPI, and Django Rest Framework.
- A reference point for GraphQL migration because of my open-source work with the **strawberry-graphql** library. I was able to give guidance on how to implement our graphql API better.
- Leading the UI development of internal administration UI interfaces for managing consignments and carriers. My experience with **React**, **Typescript** and **Next.js** has allowed me to help the team develop these applications.
- Refactor the public io.Made.com blog. Migrate to React and Next.js and, together with the Design Team, gave it a new look.

PYTHON ITALIA - FULL STACK DEVELOPER AND CONFERENCE ORGANIZER

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

Developing and maintaining of the conference website and micro-services build with Python, Django, GraphQL, React, Next.js, Storybook, Tailwind CSS.

STRAWBERRY-GRAPHQL - CORE DEVELOPER

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

A library to create GraphQL APIs with Python, dataclasses and type hints.

· Feature development, bug fixing, user support and docs writing.

DIGITALIS - FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

DECEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2021

- Developing of a web application that allows the extraction of information from the web, get notified if anything chances on social media such as Twitter/Facebook and more, allowing our internal teams to work more effectively.
- Work on backend micro-services built using **Django** and **DRF** by either building new services or improving existing ones.
- Implemented a CI infrastructure using Jenkins to test and deploy our services to AWS on ElasticBeanstalk.
- Occasionally, helped with the React frontend building new features or bug fixing.

OT CONSULTING - WEB DEVELOPER

MAY 2016 - NOVEMBER 2019

At OT Consulting I used to be a consultant for Max Mara, an international fashion company.

- · helping them develop and maintain their ERP web applications for inventory management.
- developed support the new Italian's electronic invoice and more.

ACTIVITY

TALK "AUTOMATE CLEANING CODE IN A FEW EASY STEPS"

HTTPS://ES.TER/EUROPYTHON

In these organizations, I discovered several excellent tools and automation that improve your development experience. I talked about them in my talk at PyCon Italia, Europython and Django London meetup.

EDUCATION

COMPUTER SCIENCE DEGREE
University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, Italy

2009 - 2016

DIPLOMA OF ACCOUNTANT, COMMERCIAL EXPERT AND PROGRAMMER

I.T.C.G. Institute "Luigi Einaudi", Correggio RE, Italy

2009